Hyderabad, India +91 8555845324 srikarpanuganti08@gmail.com

Srikar Panuganti Web Developer

Portfolio: <u>srikar-io.vercel.app</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/srikarpanuganti</u> <u>github.com/srikar8968</u>

Web Developer with more than 3+ years of experience and seeking a proven process in the position of a developer to further enhance organizational worth owing to my knowledge in development and dedicated to further developing career skills at professional level to meet company targets and culture.

Work Experience

Web Developer Stratistics Market Research Consulting [UrbanSportsHub, Accuray Research] Jan 2020 – July 2022

- Revamped security layers, optimizations, testing and maintenance with improved performance score of 97+ from 63 and with a minimized downtime of 18%
- Built seamless automatic managing procedures with trending JavaScript technologies (React.js, Vue.js), and MVC Architectures(Laravel, Codelgniter)
- Implemented SPA for site administrations and multi-user role using api token management for CMS software with the help of React.js
- Worked as a sole developer and so in other 4 partnering sites, built responsive design mockups for landing pages and constantly fixing user reported defects time to time
- Preparation of test cases and test review ensured high traffic rates, page clicks, and user experience by 52%

Web Developer

Credence Apps and Reports

May 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and user experience, resulting in 94+ performance score
- Built CMS with automatic web functionalities using MVC Architecture(CodeIgniter)
- Implemented site administration and user role management with seamless leads management, resulted increase in user leads by 70%
- Maintaining site performance, logs and fixing bugs resulted in constant performance\traffic numbers
- Responsible for overseeing overall quality procedures for full life cycle of software development with 100% on-time delivery

Technologies and Languages

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(ES5, ES6), PHP, MySQL, C++

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Laravel, Codelgniter, Tailwind CSS
 Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Dream-weaver, FileZilla, Lighthouse

Education

• **Diploma in Embedded Systems,** Govt. Institute of Electronics.

May 2016 - April 2019

GPA: 8.8 | C++, Embedded C, Assembly Programming, Verilog HDL

Projects

• <u>srikar.io</u> Personal Portfolio and Blog - (Next.js, TypeScript, mdx, gsap)

• WebWynk Music app - (React.js, Spotify API, TailwindCss, Auth)

<u>Seiko Dev</u> Experimental Developer's Community - (Next.js, styled-components, gsap)

• <u>CovidTracker</u> Detailed global Covid analysis - (API, JavaScript, Bootstrap)

Certifications

• Quark Summer Technical Projects (QSTP) BITS Pilani - Certificate of Excellence

May 2021 - June 2021

• Infasta Soft Solutions - Certificate of Excellence

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

Interests